<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Kai Kunze</title>
    <link>http://kaikunze.de/categories/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Kai Kunze</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kaikunze.de/categories/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Week with Glass</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/09/20/a-week-with-glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/09/20/a-week-with-glass/</guid>
      <description>How my grandparents interact with GLASS, showed me that Google seems to be onto something. As there were a lot of researchers visiting for the Ubicomp /ISWC conferences, I could grab a Google Glass from one of the participants for a week. Thanks to the anonymous donor (to avoid speculations it was none of the people mentioned below). In the following some unsorted thoughts &amp;hellip; Sorry for typos etc. It&amp;rsquo;s more a scratch pad so I don&amp;rsquo;t forget the impressions I had.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ICDAR 2013 Talk Slides Online</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/08/26/icdar-2013-talk-slides-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/08/26/icdar-2013-talk-slides-online/</guid>
      <description>The slides for my two talks today are online now.
##The Wordometer##
 ##Reading activity recognition using an off-the-shelf EEG##
 For more details, check out the papers: * The Wordometer – Estimating the Number of Words Read Using Document Image Retrieval and Mobile Eye Tracking * Reading Activity Recognition using an off-the-shelf EEG — Detecting Reading Activities and Distinguishing Genres of Documents
They are both published at ICDAR 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recognizing Reading Activities</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/08/23/recognizing-reading-activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/08/23/recognizing-reading-activities/</guid>
      <description>Just finished my keynote talk at CBDAR (Workshop of ICDAR), got a lot of questions and have a lot of new research ideas :)
I&amp;rsquo;m pretty ignorant about Document Analysis (and Computer Vision in general), so it&amp;rsquo;s great to talk to some experts in the field. Pervasive Computing and Document Analysis are very complementary and as such interesting to combine.
Here are my talk slides, followed by the talk abstract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wordometer and Document Analysis using Pervasive Sensing</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/08/20/wordometer-and-document-analysis-using-pervasive-sensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/08/20/wordometer-and-document-analysis-using-pervasive-sensing/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of months, I got more and more interested in learning, especially reading. Loving tech and sports, I got easily hooked on the Quantified Self movement (I own a Zeo Sleeping Coach and several step counters). Seeing how measuring myself transformed me. I lost around 4 kg and feel healthier/fitter, since I started tracking. I wonder why we don&amp;rsquo;t have similar tools for our learning behavior.
So we created a simple Wordometer in our Lab, using the SMI mobile eyetracker and document image retrieval (LLAH).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activity Recognition Dagstuhl Report Online</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/04/24/ar-dagstuhl-report-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/04/24/ar-dagstuhl-report-online/</guid>
      <description>If you wonder how we spent German tax money, the summary of the Activity Recognition Dagstuhl seminar is now online.
Human Activity Recognition in Smart Environments (Dagstuhl Seminar 12492)
Here&amp;rsquo;s the abstract:
This report documents the program and the outcomes of Dagstuhl Seminar 12492 &amp;ldquo;Human Activity Recognition in Smart Environments&amp;rdquo;. We established the basis for a scientific community surrounding &amp;ldquo;activity recognition&amp;rdquo; by involving researchers from a broad range of related research fields.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>