<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Kai Kunze</title>
    <link>http://kaikunze.de/categories/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Kai Kunze</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://kaikunze.de/categories/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JST Presto Project on Open Eyewear</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2016/12/26/jst-presto-project-on-open-eyewear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2016/12/26/jst-presto-project-on-open-eyewear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited and happy to be one of few non-Japanese researchers to receive a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jst.go.jp/kisoken/presto/en/index.html&#34;&gt;JST Presto (Sakigake)&lt;/a&gt;
project grant, on the Topic Open Collective Eyewear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISWC and UbiComp in Heidelberg</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2016/11/06/iswc-and-ubicomp-in-heidelberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2016/11/06/iswc-and-ubicomp-in-heidelberg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a strange feeling to have UbiComp and ISWC so close to my home.
Amazing organization and impressive research and meeting old friends.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kai at CHI 2016</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2016/05/08/kai-at-chi-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2016/05/08/kai-at-chi-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;back @ this year&amp;rsquo;s CHI 2016. We just have 3 Late Breaking Work submissions accepted and it seems they are currently for free download at the ACM website

(so grab them while they are still hot &amp;hellip; I mean free):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Dagstuhl Seminar on Eyewear Computing</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2016/05/07/dagstuhl-seminar-on-eyewear-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2016/05/07/dagstuhl-seminar-on-eyewear-computing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;lead&#34;&gt; We took a risk in organizing the Eyewear Computing Seminar as we deviated largely from the standard model, yet I believe it payed off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back on UbiComp/ISWC in Osaka</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2015/09/28/looking-back-on-ubicompiswc-in-osaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2015/09/28/looking-back-on-ubicompiswc-in-osaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;lead&#34;&gt; It felt nice to be back in Kansai for the biggest conferences in my field.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall very pleasant and inspiring event, nice to see some old friends and meet new ones.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>After my first SIGGRAPH</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2015/09/14/after-my-first-siggraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2015/09/14/after-my-first-siggraph/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p class=&#34;lead&#34;&gt;I&#39;m impressed mostly by the Hacking/Making Studios and the interactivity/demo exhibits. Siggraph is my new favorite research conference. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Affective Wear- Recognizing facial expressions</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2015/08/18/-affective-wear/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2015/08/18/-affective-wear/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Katsutoshi Masai, one of my Master students had the idea to track facial expressions using low cost sensors in glasses. Quite nice work ;)

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9PMzpsDg518&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Super Human Sports: Augmenting Blind Soccer</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2015/02/18/my-first-blind-soccer-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2015/02/18/my-first-blind-soccer-training/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m getting more and more fascinated by augmenting Blind Soccer. After 3 blind soccer trainings, we had now a couple of meetings to discuss how to extend and enhance the play experience.
For me there are 3 interesting points about blind soccer:
 It&amp;rsquo;s very hard to learn. Can we make it easier for blind people to learn it? If you can play it, it&amp;rsquo;s very fast and empowering. We train with a soccer player from the Japanese national team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31C3 Talk Slides: Eye Wear Computing</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2015/02/09/31c3-talk-slides-eye-wear-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2015/02/09/31c3-talk-slides-eye-wear-computing/</guid>
      <description>Here are the video and slides from my talk. Hope you like it. Please if you have some critique write me a mail.
I got tremendous, positive feedback. Thanks a lot! Even Heise had a news post about it. http://www.heise.de/newsticker/meldung/31C3-Mit-smarten-Brillen-das-Gehirn-ausforschen-2507482.html (Although I cannot and don&amp;rsquo;t want to read your thoughts, as the article implies ;-) ).
Video on Youtube: 
Slides on Speakerdeck: 
I got mixed some feedback on twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>31C3 Aftermath</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2015/01/17/31c3-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2015/01/17/31c3-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>Finally, I have a little time to write about the congress. As the last couple of years, I attended the 31st Chaos Communication Congress between Christmas and New Year. Here&amp;rsquo;s my talk selection in random order (I definitely forgot some as I haven&amp;rsquo;t watched all):
The Machine to be Another great research and talk. Mesmerizing, I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about how to use this effect for my work ;)
From Computation to Consciousness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eye-Wear Computing</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/11/30/eyewear-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/11/30/eyewear-computing/</guid>
      <description>Smart glasses and, in general, eyewear are a fairly novel device class with a lot of possibilities for unobtrusive activity tracking. That&#39;s why I&#39;m very excited to be working in the Team of Masahiko Inami Sensei at Keio Media Design to do research on J!NS MEME.
You might have seen the J!NS academic videos  by now, I added embedded versions to the end of the post.
Bellow is the full video of the sneak peek of our work in the J!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Glass for Older Adults</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/08/24/google-glass-for-eldery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/08/24/google-glass-for-eldery/</guid>
      <description>As the first article about my grandparents using Google Glass received a lot of interest, I decided to delve a little bit more into the topic.
My grandparents conducted a longer Google Glass usability study for me. I&amp;rsquo;m happy they agreed that I can use their images and insights to share here.
##Evaluation of the Current Google Glass
My grandparents mentioned that the current functionality of the device is quite limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking forward to ISWC/Ubicomp 2014</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/08/10/looking-forward-to-iswcubicomp-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/08/10/looking-forward-to-iswcubicomp-2014/</guid>
      <description>With roughly around 1 month to go, we are busy with demo preparations etc. I hope to see you in Seattle. This year we have again a couple papers outline work from our students. Attached is a list with draft versions of the papers. I will write a bit about each topic in the next coming weeks.
Oh and if you attend please think about stopping by our Workshop on Ubiquitous Technologies for Augmenting the Human Mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Human 2014</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/03/19/augmented-human-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/03/19/augmented-human-2014/</guid>
      <description>Innovative research, that makes you first laugh and then think. The conference develops into one of my favorite venues.
Ok, I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;a bit&amp;rdquo; biased as I&amp;rsquo;m one of the conference co-chairs. Still I enjoyed this years Augmented Human. Below is the tag cloud from all abstracts, to give you a brief overview about the topics.
Considering the small size of the conference, the quality of the work is exceptional. It&amp;rsquo;s not one of the conferences that gets the rejected papers from CHI, Ubicomp, PerComp etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beyond FuturICT</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/03/05/attending-the-symposium-on-service-systems-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/03/05/attending-the-symposium-on-service-systems-science/</guid>
      <description>Attending the International Symposium on Service Systems Science on the 26.02.2014 in Tokyo, I got a glimpse on how the next steps of FuturICT and how similar projects and efforts are on their way in Japan. Although the FuturICT project did not get funding from the EU so far (I still believe this was a grave mistake), I can see that the spirit and our ideas live on. The Japanese COI-T Program focuses on the same issues and problems as FuturICT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glass Talk at Hacker News Kansai</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/02/13/glass-talk-at-hacker-news-kansai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/02/13/glass-talk-at-hacker-news-kansai/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Google Glass to Hacker News Kansai Community was a lot of fun. I&amp;rsquo;m sorry it took so long to put online. Too much to do, especially due to Augmented Human 2014 (really looking forward to the beginning of march) :)
As part of our monthly Hacker News meetupin Kansai, I gave a small introduction on how to use (and hack for) Google Glass. 
The slides are also available as pdf download (7 MB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at 30C3</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2014/01/28/looking-back-at-30c3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2014/01/28/looking-back-at-30c3/</guid>
      <description>Impressions and Talk Recommendations. Finally, a couple of days with normal people ...
Honestly I was impressed by the professionalism of the 30th Chaos Communication Congress. It changed a lot from the last time I visited ( 25c3), grew bigger without loosing its atmosphere. With the assemblies and workshops the event starts to get more and more interactive.
##Talk Recommendations##
I link to the youtube streams of the recordings yet you can get them also over at media.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>30C3 Toward a Cognitive Quantified Self</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/12/28/30c3-toward-a-cognitive-quantified-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/12/28/30c3-toward-a-cognitive-quantified-self/</guid>
      <description>Discussing activity recognition for the Mind and its potential applications. Here are my talk slides for my 30c3 talk &amp;hellip; Sorry it took so long. Thanks for the great feedback, will write a bit more if I have sometime ;)
The video is also online. This happened very quick after the event. I&amp;rsquo;m impressed by the 30c3 content team.
  Thanks a lot for the great reviews and suggestions. They are highly appreciated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Glass</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/12/22/hacking-glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/12/22/hacking-glass/</guid>
      <description>So I got my hands on another Glass device and can now play with it a bit longer. Disclaimer: Rooting and flashing your device voids your warranty and can brick your Glass. Also you won&amp;rsquo;t receive OTA updates afterwards. This is not an instruction manual. I just use it as a scratch pad to give a record what I did and what worked for me. The commands below will erase all data on your device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bits and Bytes instead of a Bookshelf</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/11/29/bits-and-bytes-instead-of-a-book-shelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/11/29/bits-and-bytes-instead-of-a-book-shelf/</guid>
      <description>An interview made me wonder about how reading habits are changing and how we will narrate stories in the future. Recently, I gave an interview for the German online issue of the Scientific American (Spectrum der Wissenschaft) for a special about reading habits (in German, paywall).
As I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the topic, I often hear that &amp;ldquo;endless scrolling&amp;rdquo; is bad as it destroys the mental map we make of books and pages or that reading from backlit screens is eye-straining inducing headaches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazing Okinawa - Attending the ASVAI Workshop</title>
      <link>http://kaikunze.de/2013/11/05/amazing-okinawa-attending-the-asvai-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://kaikunze.de/2013/11/05/amazing-okinawa-attending-the-asvai-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Cool research discussions at a nice location. The workshop was perfect fit to my research interests.
The ASVAI workshop gave a good overview about several research efforts part of and related to the JST CREST and the JSPS Core-to-Core Sanken Program.
Prof. Yasushi Yagi showed how to infer intention from gait analysis. Interestingly, he showed research about the relationship of gaze and gait.
Dr. Alireza Fathi presented cool work about ego centric cameras.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>